Nand
2026 job.
>> The hat was already creased, too. I like
that. I like that. Little prim. He good
to go.
>> Well, how does it feel? You walked in to
balconies of people cheering for you.
You look and you see Tim Brown, Eric
Allen. You're seeing these Hall of
Famers. Jim Plunkett, Raider greats are
here. What was your feeling the moment
you walked through the doors here at the
facility? Well, when I walked through
the facility, it was just such a
blessing to see all the Raider legends
themselves, Hall of Famers, former
Heisen Trophy winners.
>> Every corner you turn in the facility,
it's a new Raider legend or new someone,
you're trying to pinch yourself. I'm
just so blessed with the opportunity and
it shows what a first class organization
this is. The support, whether it's the
alumni, the coaching staff, the
teammates, everyone that's reached out.
I'm so happy to be a part of it.
>> Yeah. You know, um, you should feel real
real special because JJ don't go to the
balcony for too many people.
>> He was like a little kid when he is
coming.
>> I came out there and I, you know, took a
little video of the kid coming. Um, but
one thing I did see, man, that that kind
of stood out to me, man, was your
attention to detail.
>> Okay.
>> Because you walked in and you seen that
shield and you said, "Oh, shoot.
Shield." So, can you take us through
that moment right there? You didn't want
to get down and do no push-ups, but you
knew you can't step on that shield.
>> Yeah. Especially as a rookie, you're
you're trying to limit rookie mistakes.
>> And in the top 30, they said no stepping
on the shield. That's always been a big
thing. So,
>> so what to sell the shield? I was so
overjoyed.
>> I was like blacked out at that point. I
like had to see the shield. My senses,
my my spidey senses came back to me.
>> There you maybe like a couple inches
away from
>> but what I like is your eyes. They
didn't go down. You're still able to see
the defense, you know, and still step
off. Good job, man.
>> You need to, you know, you need to be
able to evade and step up in the pocket.
Although we have a great offensive line,
so that's not a problem, but you know,
keeping the eyes on the field so I can
throw it to the playmakers.
>> Yeah. One question I have to Who was
your compass? I mean, like when I was
young and playing football, you know,
either a Cliff Branch or my Marcus Allen
who grew up in San Diego was like my
compass. Like that's kind of how I want
to play the game. Who was your compass
uh throughout this time?
>> Well, funny enough, my my compass was
Tom Brady. He's a minority owner here,
which is fantastic. It's like I what a
dream come true. I'm going to try to
absorb every single resource and
intelligence that that football
intelligence that he's willing to give
up to me and take it into my own game.
And we're not this, you know,
>> you know, I have a lot to learn and a
long long long way to go and everyone's
a different player, but looking forward
to taking all the nuggets I can from
him,
>> right?
>> And the reason I loved him and watching
him so much is because of attention to
detail. Yeah.
>> How intentional he was with everything.
>> Yeah.
>> Whether it was a bad play and a bad
coverage, he didn't run it. He checked
it. He knew. He was very cerebral.
Uh-huh.
>> His leadership, his leadership, whether
it was down 28 to3 against the Falcons,
his entire career, leadership and
culture is always at the forefront of
successful organizations.
>> Okay.
>> And then number three is the way he was
accurate and the way that he just played
the game.
>> The way he played the game, the way that
he was always going to be the point
guard on the field.
>> He was going to make sure that he got
his playmakers the balls. He's gonna
help his offensive line, help his
defense, and let the other guy shine.
>> Yeah. Well, I'm gonna follow up with
that. What would you have done in the
fog that day in 2002 when Tom Brady
playing the
>> even
well well well as as a Raider now
definitely a fumble. There you go. There
you go.
>> There you go. That's what I like, you
know, I don't want to, you know, I'm a
Raider. I also don't want to, you know,
piss off any owners.
>> All right. It was a fumble. Tom knows a
fumble, too.
>> We We sat here yesterday. He's admitted
it before. He admitted it before.
>> There you go. He'll be honest with you
about it. Uh we sat here and we listed I
went through game by game where things
didn't go your way at the end of your
college career whether whether it was
Iowa, Oregon, uh Penn State, Miami where
you know you get hit in the mouth, Ohio
State, you get hit in the mouth and then
you came back. Where did that toughness
come from in you?
>> Yeah, the toughness came from my parents
and especially my mom. My mom struggles
with multiple scerosis and where she's
essentially paralyzed. But seeing her
have a smile on her face every single
day
>> means the world to me. And it doesn't
allow me an excuse to have a bad day,
bad practice, bad game. Because when I
see her there fighting,
it inspires me. And it gives me this
unwavering optimism where no matter what
happens, whatever resilient bump
>> or bump in the road happens, I know
instead of falling down, I'm just going
to catapult off of that and learn from
him and get better.
>> Oh, you got me as a mom. You just got
me.
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. We all love our
mamas, man. So, you know what I mean?
Kudos to you. Um, I had a chance to play
with Brett Favre.
>> Yeah.
>> I had a chance to play with Aaron
Rogers. Um, really good leaders and I
got on here with number four. You see my
notes? Well, get on your
get on your head.
>> I got on here number 12. We'll slap
this.
>> And the main reason why I say that is
what kind of leader are you? Because
these dudes playing with these, they
weren't worried about you my friend. EA
got to do your job. Yeah. You know what
I'm saying? And if we do, if you do your
job, we're going to win. I'mma make sure
you going to do your job cuz I'mma stay
on you. I'm the leader of this this
team. You are a very humble kid. This
your team, dog.
>> Whether you whether you like it or not
right now, this is your team walking
into the building. You know what I'm
saying? So, what kind of leader are you
out there on the football field? We know
you're a humble dude, but how do you
lead? How do you get on your players?
>> Although I've came off as a as very
humble and pretty fuzzy and warm, at the
end of my Indiana career, when you have
that equity, you're able to be like
number four and number 12. And if you
ask my teammates, that's stuff that I
that I was. I wasn't always a nice guy.
I was an a-hole sometimes because I
wanted everyone to do their 111th,
everyone to do their job, hold everyone
to a high standard. However, coming to a
new organization, starting from the
bottom of the totem pole, I believe that
leadership is earned. not given. And
there's so many amazing leaders on this
team. And I think especially as a
quarterback, the two things you need to
be a leader is number one, you got to
play well. Play well. I always respect
you. That's number four. Number 12, both
Hall of Famers. You got to play well.
You got to do your job before you can
hold other people accountable. And
number two, you got to create equity.
You got to create equity. Whether it's
work ethic,
>> whether it's caring about your teammates
and connecting them on the personal
level
>> and just then just being one of the
guys.
>> There it is. When you have that equity,
I when you have that player equity and
then also have that performance equity,
that is when you take that corner and
then you could have that advanced
leadership techniques of holding people
accountable because they know not only
do you do your job, you go above and
beyond. And that was something I was
able to experience at the end of my
career at Indiana. There you go.
>> However, now I'm starting from the
bottom of the tonal and there's so many
great leaders, offense, defense, special
teams, coaches, owners that I can learn
from. So right now I'm just trying to be
a sponge and build that equity, try to
perform in my job and try to connect
with my teammates.
>> Just following up on that, usually when
you're number one overall pick, you're
going to a team that has the number one
pick for a reason, right there. There's
not a lot of pieces in place. Look at
what John Spy did in this off season.
And the fact that you're walking into
Clint Kubak as a head coach, Tom Brady
as a resource, you have uh first round
draft picks as two of your skilled
players and Brock Bowers and Ashton
Genty. they just bring in the best
center in the NFL. Do you feel like when
you assess the situation you're walking
into, it's a step ahead of what a lot of
number one overall picks walk into?
>> I believe it's a huge step ahead. And
it's huge step up ahead because not only
are all those great talents, they're
also great people.
>> They're great people. And that's what's
so first class about this organization.
And I'm just trying to prove it that I
that I belong. I'm one of them. And so
I'm just looking forward to rookie mini
camp in a couple of of days. I can prove
it and just start diving my dive my head
into the offense.
>> I just can't wait for the cigars in the
first tattoo. When Max Crosby takes
them, we get the first tattoo after, you
know, the wins. We're going to we're
going to we're going to get that. Thanks
so much, Rando Jones. It's such a
pleasure meeting you. Enjoy the ride.